Register of the United States Army European Command, Historical Division Typescript Studies, 1945-1954
Hoover Institution Archives
- A-Series manuscripts. (Box 1-5)
  - A-965 By Generalmajor Carl Wagener; 61 pp, 18 illus; EUCOM mimeograph, German Report Series; 1948. Evaluation of the Ardennes offensive; subsequent fighting of Army Group B to Mar. 1945. (Box 4)
  - A-966 Role of 589th Military Government Area Hq. in the Battle Around Liege (Autumn 1944). By Generalleutnant Bernhard von Clear; 14 pp; 1946. (Box 4)
  - A-967 Northern France. By Generalleutnant Frhr. von Boineburg; 7 pp; 1946. 325th Security Division in combat on the Swiss border, autumn 1944. (Box 4)
  - A-968 LXXXIV Corps (28 Jul.-20 Aug. 1944). By Generalleutnant Otto Elfeldt; 10 pp; 1946. By the corps commander. (Box 4)
  - A-969 II Parachute Corps in Northern France (26 Jul.-5 Aug. 1944). By General der Fallschirmtruppen Eugen Meindl; 11 pp; 1946. Comments by the corps commander. See also MS # A-923. (Box 4)
  - A-970 Remagen Bridgehea D--LIII Corps. By Generalleutnant F. Bayerlein; 13 pp; 1946. Extracts for the war diary of Panzer Lehr Division. (Box 4)
  - A-971 First Battle of Aachen (16-22 Sep. 1944). By Generalleutnant Gerhard Engel; 211 pp, 2 illus; 1946. By the commander of the 12th Infantry Division. (Box 4)
  - A-972 The Rhineland Campaign (15-21 Sep. 1944). By Generalleutnant Kurt von Muehlen; 21 pp; 1946. 559th Volks Grenadier Division, 1944-45. (Box 4)
  - A-974 Normandy--Seventh Army (29 Jun-24 Jul. 1944). By Generaloberst Paul Hausser; 37 pp, 8 illus; 1946. By the army commander. (Box 4)
  - A-975 275th Infantry Division (Dec. 1943-Jun. 1944). By Generalleutnant H. Schmidt; 11 pp. Organization and commitment in Brittany. (Box 4)
  - A-976 3d Panzer Grenadier Division in the Inden Bridgehead (27-29 Nov. 1944). By Generalmajor Walter Denkert; 6 pp, 1 illus; 1945. Defense of the Inden bridgehead (Roer). (Box 4)
  - A-977 The German Ardennes Offensive. By Maj. Herbert Buechs; 49 pp; 1945. Planning and preparations by OKW. (Box 4)
  - A-978 Commitment of the 3d Panzer Grenadier Division during the Ardennes Offensive. By Generalmajor Walter Denkert; 5 pp; 1946. (Box 4)
  - A-979 3d Panzer Grenadier Division in the Battle of Aachen (Oct. 1944). By Generalmajor Walter Denkert; 9 pp, 1 illus. (Box 4)
  - A-980 St. Nazaire Fortress (1944). By Generalmajor M. Huenten; 8 pp; 1946. Incomplete. (Box 5)
  - A-981 St. Nazaire Fortress, Southern Part, 1944. By Generalmajor M. Huenten; 13 pp. (Box 5)
  - A-983 353d Infantry Division (Nov. 1943-24 Jul. 1944). By Generalleutnant Paul Mahlmann; 19 pp, 10 illus; 1946. Organization in Frittany, 1943; move to Normandy, late June 1944; combat against American forces, Jul. 1944. Serves as prologue to MS # A-984. (Box 5)
  - A-984 353d Infantry Division (24 Jul.-14 Sep. 1944). By Generalleutnant Paul to Mahlmann; 4 vols, 50 pp, 45 illus; 1946. Avranches; Falaise, Seine to the (Box 5)
  - A-987 Meuse; Meuse to the Siegfried Line. (Four manuscripts in one folder.) (Box 5)
  - A-989 The Battle of the Aachen Sector (Sep.-Nov. 1944). By General der to Infanterie Friedrich Koechling; 7 vols, 38 pp; 1945. Questionnaires on the A-995 action of LXXXI Corps in the Aachen area answered by the corps commander. (Box 5)
  - A-995. (Box 5)
  - A-996 Battles in the Aachen Sector (16 Nov.-16 Dec. 1944). By General der Infanterie Friedrich Koechling; 14 pp; 1946. Continuation of MSS # A- 989-995. (Box 5)
  - A-997 Battles in the Aachen Sector (Sep.-Nov. 1944). By General der Infanterie Friedrich Koechling; 37 pp; 1946. Comments by the LXXXI Corps commander on MSS # A-989-996. (Box 5)
  - A-998 Battles in the Aachen Sector (Sep.-Nov. 1944). By General der Infanterie Friedrich Koechling; 9 pp. Corrections to MSS # A-989 through A-995. (Box 5)
- B Series Manuscripts. (Box 5-28)
  When a systematic listing of studies was begun in mid-1946, manuscripts on hand but still untranslated were listed in the B series. Manuscripts continued to be added until July 1948. The bulk of these studies are narrative histories of units on the Western Front, division to army group level. However, this series is the longest and most varied in subject matter and quality. Many of the studies are available in English only as draft translations. In some cases dates of writing are unknown and have been omitted without comment. PLEASE NOTE: Those manuscript numbers followed by an asterisk indicate publications that are NOT included on the National Archives' M1035 fiche. B-series manuscript titles are drawn from the Guide to Foreign Military Studies, 1945-54; Catalog & Index (Headquarters, United States Army, Europe, 1954)
  - B-001 LXXXII Corps (1 Jan.-28 Aug. 1944). By General der Artillerie Hans Sinnhuber; 12 pp; 1946. Preparations for coast defense. (Box 5)
  - B-002 LXXXII Corps (28 Aug.-7 Sep. 1944). By General der Artillerie Hans Sinnhuber; 2 pp; 1946. (Box 5)
  - B-003 Report Concerning My Activity as Commander of the Seventh and First German Army Rear Areas (Aug.-Sep. 1944). By Generalmajor Curt Souchay; 12 pp; 1946. Operations in France. (Box 5)
  - B-004 719th Infantry Division (Aug.-18 Sep. 1944). By Generalleutnant Karl Sievers; 10 pp; 1946. Operations in Belgium. (Box 5)
  - B-005 Loire Seekommandant (6 Jul.-11 Aug. 1944). By Konteradmiral Hans Mirow; 15 pp; 1946. A naval coast defense headquarters. (Box 5)
  - B-006 LXXX Corps (Aug.-12 Sep. 1944). By General der Infanterie Dr. Franz (Box 5)
  - B-006a Beyer; 2 vols, 25 pp; 1946. Withdrawal from France. (Box 5)
  - B-007 276 Infantry Division (1 Jan.-20 Aug. 1944). By Generalleutnant Kurt Badinski; 40 pp; 1946. Operations in Normandy. (Box 5)
  - B-008 346th Infantry Division (Feb.-24 Jul. 1944). By Oberst i.G. Paul Frank; 22 pp, 6 illus; 1946. Defensive operations in Normandy. (Box 5)
  - B-009 277th Infantry Division (15 Apr.-25 Jul. 1944). By General der Nachrichtentruppen Albert Praun; 11 pp, 2 illus; 1946. (Box 5)
  - B-010 91st Airborne Division (10 Jul.-Aug. 1944). By Generalmajor Eugen Koenig; 8 pp. Operations in Normandy. (Box 5)
  - B-011 16th Luftwaffe Field Division (Invasion Possibilities in Holland). By Generalleutnant Karl Sievers; 1 p. (Box 5)
  - B-012 89th Infantry Division (Mar.-6 Aug. 1944). By Oberst Hasso Neitzel; 8 pp; 1946. Of limited historical value. (English text not available in USAREUR.) (Box 5)
  - B-013 5th Fight Division (1 Mar.-28 Aug. 1944). By Generalmajor (Lw) Karl Hentschel; 10 pp, 2 illus; 1946. (Box 5)
  - B-014 17th Luftwaffe Field Division (Pre-Invasion 24 Jul. 1944). By Generalleutnant Hans Hoecker; 30 pp, 3 illus; 1946. Coast defense at Dieppe and LeHavre. (Box 5)
  - B-015 Defense of Paris. By Generalleutnant Wilhelm Frhr. von Boineburg; 9 pp, 1 illus; 1946. (Box 5)
  - B-0043 Vosges Defense (8 Aug.-15 Oct. 1944). By General der Infanterie Hans Joachim Schmidt; 5 pp, 1 illus. (Box 6)
  - B-016a 861st Grenadier Regiment (May-11 Sep. 1944). By Generalmajor Erich (Box 6)
  - B-016b Buescher; 2 vols, 27 pp, 3 illus; 1946. (Box 6)
  - B-019 Report of von Geyr. By Generalleutnant Goetz von dem Knesebeck; 8 pp. The author quotes from memory von Geyr's Normandy situation estimate of 15 Jun. 1944, submitted to the Inspector General of Panzer Troops (Guderian). Included in MS # B-466. (Box 6)
  - B-020* 3d Parachute Division (6 Jun.-24 Jul. 1944). By Generalleutnant Rich. Schimpf; 12 pp, 6 illus; 1947. In France; a valuable historical study by the division commander. (English text not available in USAREUR.) (Box 6)
  - B-020a 3d Parachute Division (6 Jun. 1944-8 Mar. 1945). By Generalleutnant to Rich. Schimpf; 10 pp; 1946. Brief answers to questionnaires on B-020d Normandy, northern France, the Ardennes, and the Rhineland campaign. (English text not available in USAREUR.) (Box 6)
  - B-021 352d Infantry Div.--Special Questions (Normandy). By Oberstleutnant Fritz Ziegelmann; 5 pp; 1946. (Box 6)
  - B-022 The Resistance Movement in the West. By Oberstleutnant Fritz Ziegelmann; 12 pp; OCMH multilith; 1953. The French Resistance in 1944. (Box 6)
  - B-024 560th Volks Grenadier Division (11 Nov. 1944). By Generalmajor Rudolf Bader; 11 pp, 1 illus; 1946. (Box 6)
  - B-025 989th Grenadier Regiment (14-17 Dec. 1944). By Oberst Georg Fieger; 6 pp; 1946. (Box 6)
  - B-026 Effect of Ardennes Offensive on Army Group G. By SS Generaloberst Paul Hausser; 34 pp; 1946. By the army group commander. The sections dealing with events prior to 23 Jan. 1945 are of doubtful value as the author only took over command on that date. (Box 6)
  - B-027 560th Volks Grenadier Division (15-29 Dec. 1944) and 12th Volks Grenadier Div. (1-28 Jan. 1945). By Generalmajor Rud. Langhaeuser; 67 pp, 17 illus; 1946. (Box 6)
  - B-029 LIII Corps (8 Dec. 1944-21 Jan. 1945). By General der Kavallerie Edwin Graf Rothkirch; 1 p; 1946. By the corps commander. (Box 6)
  - B-030 LXXXV Corps (1 Dec. 1944-10 Jan. 1945). By General der Infanterie Baptist Kniess; 8 pp; 1946. (Box 6)
  - B-032 LIII Corps (1 Dec. 1944-22 Jan. 1945). By Oberst i.G. Werner Bodenstein; 13 pp. Participation in the Ardennes offensive; report by the corps chief of staff. (Box 6)
  - B-033 LXXIV Corps (Ardennes). By General der Infanterie Carl Puechler; 3 pp; 1946. South flank of the Ardennes. (Box 6)
  - B-034 OKW War Diary (1 Apr.-18 Dec. 1944): The West. By Major Percy F. Schramm; 349 pp; 1947. Based on OKW files. Draft translation only. (Box 6)
  - B-034a Clarification of "Der Westen." By General der ARtillerie Walter Warlimont; 11 pp; 1951. When did Hitler finally order construction of a rear defense line in France? (Box 6)
  - B-035 The FFI Before and After D-Day (1944). By Commandant Rogé; 51 pp, 1 illus. Statistics require careful checking. (Box 6)
  - B-037 Fifth Panzer Army (15 Sep.-12 Oct. 1944). By General der Panzertruppen Hasso von Manteuffel; 43 pp. The fighting in Lorraine described by the army commander. (Box 6)
  - B-038 116th Panzer Division (Ardennes). By Generalmajor Siegfried von Waldenburg; 17 pp. Answers of the division commander to a special questionnaire. (Box 6)
  - B-039 XIII Corps (1-15 Jan. 1945). By General der Infanterie Hans Felber; 22 pp; 1946. Defensive fighting in the Ardennes. (Box 6)
  - B-040 26th Volks Grenadier Division in the Ardennes Offensive. By Generalmajor Heinz Kokott; 16 pp. By the division commander. (Box 6)
  - B-041 167th Volks Grenadier Division (24 Dec. 1944-Feb. 1945). Corps Hoecker (1-10 Mar. 1945) and 59th Infantry Division (20 Mar.-24 Apr. 1945). By Generalleutnant Hans Hoecker; 43 pp; 1946. (Box 6)
  - B-042 462d Replacement Division. By Generalleutnant Walter Krause; 14 pp, 1 illus. A replacement division staff in the defense of Metz. (Box 6)
  - B-044 Wehrkreis VI (15 Sep. 1944-21 Mar. 1945). By General der Infanterie Franz Maltenklott; 7 pp. (Box 6)
  - B-045 79th Volks Grenadier Division (8 Jan.-26 Feb. 1945). 364th Infantry Division (3-27 Mar. 1945). 3d Parachute Division (8-16 Apr. 1945). By Oberst Kurt Hummel; 8 pp; 1946. Operations in the Rhineland. (Box 7)
  - B-046 XIII Corps Artillery (Dec. 1944-Feb. 1945). Corps Felber Artillery (Dec. 1944-Feb. 1945). By Generalmajor Jobst Freiherr von Buddenbrock; 8 pp; 1946. (Box 7)
  - B-047 LXIII Corps Artillery (1 Dec. 1944-8 Feb. 1945). By Generalmajor Wilhelm Metger; 6 pp; 1946. Report by the corps artillery commander on combat in upper Alsace. (Box 7)
  - B-048 Fifth Panzer Army Surgeon (1944-45). By Generalarzt Dr. Reiter; 4 pp. A report on the writer's activities during the last months of the war. (Box 7)
  - B-049 Panzer Lehr Division (12-30 Jan. 1945). By Generalleutnant Fritz Bayerlein; 4 pp, 1 illus; 1946. Withdrawal from action in the Ardennes. (Box 7)
  - B-050 LXIV Corps Actions (28 Aug. 1944-28 Jan. 1945). By General der Infanterie Helmuth Thumm; 18 pp; 1946. The fighting in upper Alsace. (Box 7)
  - B-051 See MS # B-093. (Box 7)
  - B-052 XIII Corps (18 Feb.-21 Mar. 1945). By Generalleutnant Ralph von Oriola; 36 pp; 1946. Operations west of the Rhine. (Box 7)
  - B-053 Corps Bayerlein (11 Feb.-5 Mar. 1945). By Generalleutnant Fritz Bayerlein; 19 pp, 14 illus. Operations west of the Rhine; a record based on the corps commander's personal diaries. (Box 7)
  - B-054 Besançon (3-5 Sep. 1944). By Generalmajor Paul v. Felbert; 16 pp, 4 illus. Security activities. (Box 7)
  - B-055 Army Group B, Engineer Staff 113 (15 Jun.-5 Sept. 1944). By Generalmajor Hermann Janowski; 11 pp; 1946. Engineer operations to restore river crossings on the Seine and to destroy bridges during the withdrawal. (Box 7)
  - B-056 277th Infantry Division (25 Jul.-10 Sep. 1944). By General der Nachrichtentruppen Albert Praun; 8 pp, 3 illus; 1946. The fighting in Normandy. (Box 7)
  - B-057 59th Infantry Division (19 Aug.-5 Sep. 1944). By Generalleutnant Walter Poppe; 15 pp, 1 illus; 1946. Operations in northern France and Belgium; withdrawal to the Scheldt estuary. (Box 7)
  - B-058 116th Panzer Division (21 Aug.-19 Sep. 1944). By Generalmajor H. Voigtsberger; 17 pp; 1946. From the Falaise pocket to the West Wall. An account of rearguard action by an armored mobile unit against enveloping pursuit. (Box 7)
  - B-059 Feldkommandant 987 (19 Oct. 1944-25 Mar. 1945). By Generalmajor Hans Moench; 17 pp. A security-unit in Alsace and the Palatinate. (Box 7)
  - B-060 Wehrkreis XII (10 Sep. 1944-21 Mar. 1945). By.Generalleutnant Kurt von Berg; 10 pp, 2 illus; 1946. (Box 7)
  - B-061 36th Volks Grenadier Division (18-26 Mar 1945). By Generalmajor Helmut Kleikamp; 13 pp, 1 illus; 1946. Combat in the Rhineland. (Box 7)
  - B-062 2d Mountain Division (27 Feb-23 Mar 1945). By Generalleutnant Willibald Utz; 18 pp, 1 illus; 1946. (Box 7)
  - B-063 Wehrkreis XII (7-21 Mar. 1945). By Generalmajor Hans Boelsen; 9 pp; 1946. (Box 7)
  - B-064 Festungs Pionier Kommandeur XXI, (Sep. 1944-Apr. 1945). By Generalmajor Rob. Eimler; 7 pp, 3 illus; 1946. A fortress engineer staff on both banks of the lower Rhine; organization and construction of fortified positions. (Box 7)
  - B-065 Hoehere Kommando Eiffel (Aug. 1944-Apr. 1945). By General der Artillerie Herbert Loch; 16 pp; 1946. Reconnaissance. and improvement of rear positions in the Eiffel Mountains. (Box 7)
  - B-066 LXXXII Corps (2 Dec. 1944-27 Mar. 1945). By Oberst i.G. Ludwig Graf von Ingelheim; 53 pp, 14 illus; 1946. On the Saar. and in the Palatinate. Based on diaries and recollections of the commanders and general staff officers concerned. (Box 7)
  - B-067 352d Volks Grenadier Division (16 Dec. 1944-25 Jan. 1945). By Generalmajor Erich Schmidt; 8 pp; 1946. (Box 7)
  - B-068 3d Panzer Grenadier Division (Ardennes). By Generalmajor Walter Denkert; 12 pp; 1946. Reconditioning of troops near the front. (Box 7)
  - B-069 363d Volks Grenadier Division (1 Dec. 1944-8 Feb. 1945). By Generalleutnant Augustin Denting; 16 pp, 4 illus; 1946. Defense of the Aachen area. (Box 7)
  - B-070 79th Volks Grenadier Division (30 Dec. 1944-31 Jan. 1945). By Oberst Curt Hummel; 32 pp, 7 illus; 1946. (Box 7)
  - B-071 See MS # B-117. (Box 7)
  - B-072 Army Group B, Engineer Staff 113 (Mar. 1945). By Generalmajor Herm. Janowski; 18 pp, 4 illus. Crossing the lower Rhine in March 1945. (Box 7)
  - B-073 212th Volks Grenadier Division (Ardennes). By Generalleutnant Franz Sensfuss; 8 pp,1 illus; 1946. Answers to a questionnaire. (Box 7)
  - B-074 338th Infantry Division (1 Jan-9 Feb. 1945). By Generalmajor Wolf Ebert; 8 pp: 2 illus. Operations in Alsace. (Box 7)
  - B-075 LXXXIX Corps (22 Nov. 1944-13 Jan., 1945). By General. Der to Infanterie Gustav Hoehne; 3 vols, 22 pp, 1 illus; 1946. By the corps B-077 commander. (Box 7)
  - B-078 See MS # A-999. (Box 7)
  - B-081 LXXX Corps (13 Sep. 1944-23 Mar. 1945). By General der Infanterie to Dr. Franz Beyer; 2 vols, 74 pp; 1946. By the corps commander. (Box 8)
  - B-082 (Box 8)
  - B-083 Army Commandant Muehlhausen (Jul. 1944-Jan. 1945). By Generalmlajor Hermann Harttmann; 12 pp. Organization and fighting. (Box 8)
  - B-084 First Parachute Army (20 Nov. 1944-21 Mar. 1945). By General der Fallschirmtruppe Alfred_Schlemm; 20 pp. Defensive operations described by the army commander. (Box 8)
  - B-085 49th Infantry Division (25 Jul.-10 Oct. 1944). By Generalleutnant to Siegfr. Macholz; 11 pp; 1946. (Box 8)
  - B-086 (Box 8)
  - B-087 XIII Corps (Dec. 1944-Mar. 1945). By Major Wolfgang Gaebelein; 9 pp; 1946. (Box 8)
  - B-088 Saarburg (18 Sep.-12 Oct. 1944). By Generalleutnant Bernhard von Claer; 18 pp. (Box 8)
  - B-089 256th Volks Grenadier Division (Nov. 1944-8 Apr 1945). By Generalmajor Gerhard Franz; 11 pp; 1946. Combat on both banks of the Rhine. (Box 8)
  - B-090 416th Infantry Division (Oct. 1944-5 Apr. 1945). By Generalleutnant Kurt Pflieger; 11 pp; 1946. (Box 8)
  - B-091 First Army Rear Area (1 Oct. 1944-21 Mar. 1945). By Generalleutnant Otto Kohl; 7 pp; 1 illus. Defense against airborne landings. (Box 8)
  - B-092 326th Volks Grenadier Division (16 Dec. 1944-25 Jan 1945). By Generalmajor Erwin Kaschner; 10 pp, 6 illus. Operations in the Ardennes offensive. (Box 8)
  - B-093 II Parachute Corps (15 Sep. 1944-21 Mar. 1945). (Revision of MS # B- 051. By General der Fallschirmtruppen Eug. Meindl; 21 pp; 6 illus; 1947. Operations on the lower Rhine. (Box 8)
  - B-094 Military Commander France. By Generalmajor Manfred Mueller; 8 pp. Organization and administration. (Box 8)
  - B-095 Army Group G (Nov. 1944-Jan. 1945). By Oberst Horst Wilutzky; 40 pp. By the army group operations officer. (Box 8)
  - B-096 Corps Felber (9-31 Dec. 1944). By General der Infanterie Hans Felber; 8 pp; 1946. (Box 8)
  - B-097 79th Volks Grenadier Division (1 Feb.-2 Mar. 1945). By Oberst Kurt Hummel; 6 pp, 1946. (Box 8)
  - B-098 353d Infantry Division (2-22 Mar. 1945). By Oberst Kurt Hummel; 6 pp, 1 illus; 1946. (Box 8)
  - B-099 LXIV Corps (28 Jan.-7 Feb. 1945). By General der Artillerie Max Grimmeis; 18 pp; 1946. (Box 8)
  - B-100 708th Volks Grenadier Division (20 Nov. 1944-14 Feb. 1945). By Generalmajor Wilhelm Bleckwenn; 10 pp, 7 illus; 1946. (Box 8)
  - B-101 LXVII Corps (26 Jan.-21 Mar. 1945). By General der Infanterie Otto Hitzfeld, 55 pp, 8 illus; 1946. From the West Wall to the Rhine (Central Army Group). An account by the corps commander. (Box 8)
  - B-102 Twenty-Fourth Army (17 Oct. 1944-5 May, 1945). By General der to Infanterie Hans Schmidt; 2 vols, 15 pp, 3 illus. Operations in the Allgau. (Box 8)
  - B-103 (Box 8)
  - B-104 2d Mountain Division (23 Mar.-6 May 1945). By Generalleutnant W. Utz; 27 pp; 1946. (Box 8)
  - B-105 Army Group B, Engineer Staff 113: Obstacle Construction East of the Rhine. By Generalmajor Hermann Janowski; 5 pp; 1946. (Box 8)
  - B-106 Linz/Donau (28 Mar.-11 May 1945). By Generalmajor Alfred Kuzmany; 4 pp. (Box 8)
  - B-107 Report Covering Operations in and around Linz, May 1945. By Generalmajor Alfred Kuzmany; 11 pp; 1946. (Box 8)
  - B-108 3d Parachute Division (9-16 Apr. 1945). By Oberst Kurt Hummel; 10 pp, 1 illus; 1945. (Box 8)
  - B-109 353d Infantry Division (23 Mar.-8 Apr. 1945). By Oberst Kurt Hummel; 9 pp; 1945. (Box 8)
  - B-110 405th Replacement and Training Division (22 Mar.-6 May 1945). By Generalleutnant Karl Faulenbach; 57 pp; 1946. (Box 8)
  - B-111 347th Infantry Division (4-10 Apr. 1945). By Generalleutnant Max Siry; 6 pp, 1 illus; 1946. (Box 8)
  - B-112 Dusseldorf (1 Mar.-15 Apr. 1945). By Generalmajor Frhr. von Uslar- Gleichen; 10 pp; 1946. (Box 8)
  - B-113 413th Replacement Division (22 Mar.-30 May 1945). By Generalleutnant Siegmund Frhr. von Schacky; 14 pp; 1946. (Box 8)
  - B-114 413th Replacement Division (4 Apr.-8 May 1945). By Generalleutnant Siegmund Frhr. von Schacky; 16 pp. (Box 8)
  - B-115- B-116 404th. Replacement Division (20 Apr.-9 May 1945) and Battle Group to Schroetter (1-11 Apr. 1945). By Generalleutnant Joseph Schroetter; 18 pp, 1946. (Box 8)
  - B-117 IV Luftwaffe Field Corps, XC Corps (18 Sep. 1944-23 Mar. 1945). By General der Infanterie Erich Peterson; 2 vols, 40 pp, 8 illus; 1946. Participation in Operation NORDWIND (lower Alsace). The English version includes MS # B-071. (Box 8)
  - B-118 LXXIV Corps (2 Oct. 1944-23 Mar. 1945). By General der Infanterie Karl Puechler; 23 pp, 1946. By the corps commander. (Box 8)
  - B-119 Wehrkreis XII (1 Nov. 1944-21 Mar. 1945). By General der Artillerie Herbert Osterkamp; 8 pp, 4 illus; 1946. By the corps area commander. (Box 8)
  - B-120 LXXXIX Corps (14 Jan.-7 Mar. 1945). By General der Infanterie Gustav Hoehne; 5 pp, 1 illus; 1946. (Box 8)
  - B-121 LXXXV Corps (25 Jan.-23 Mar. 1945). By General der Infanterie Baptist Kniess; 6 pp; 1946. Operations in the Saar. (Box 9)
  - B-122 Preparations Against Invasion. By Generalmajor R. von Gersdorff; 33 pp, 2 illus. The German situation estimate and strategy during the three phases of the campaign in Normandy and northern France to mid- September 1944. (Box 9)
  - B-123 Seventh Army (1 Feb.-21 Mar. 1945). By Generalmajor R. von Gersdorff; 52 pp; 1946. (Box 9)
  - B-124 276th Volks Grenadier Division (17-27 Mar. 45). By Oberst i.G. Werner Wagner; 25 pp, 2 illus; 1946. Rhine crossing near Boppard; defense of the east bank. (Box 9)
  - B-125 Division von Berg (22 Mar.-11 May 1945). By Generalleutnant Kurt von Berg; 12 pp; 1946. (Box 9)
  - B-126 172d Training Division (14 Jan-6 May 1945). By Generalmajor Martin Baltzer; 10 pp; 1946. (Box 9)
  - B-127 Germersheim Bridgehead (18 Feb.-25 Mar.1945). By Generalmajor E. Buescher; 11 pp; 1946. (Box 9)
  - B-128 Commander of Police, Wehrkreis XI (19 Apr. 1943-11 Apr. 1945). By Generalmajor der Ordnungspolizei Walter Keuck; 13 pp, 1 illus; 1946. (Box 9)
  - B-129 151st Field Training Division (1 Mar.-15 Jun. 1945). By Generalmajor Julius Coretti; 13 pp. (Box 9)
  - B-130 Wehrkreis VII Police (National Redoubt). By Generalmajor der Ordnungspolizei Ludwig Muhe; 7 pp; 1946. A historical report by a civilian police chief. (Box 9)
  - B-132 National Redoubt and Reich Labor Service Austria. By Generalarbeitsfuehrer Fritz Hickl; 7 pp, 1946. (Box 9)
  - B-133 Wehrkreis XVIII--Luftwaffe Liaison Officer. By Generalmajor Josef Punzert; 13 pp; 1946. National Redoubt. (Box 9)
  - B-134 710th Infantry Division (23 Apr.-8 May 1945). By Generalmajor W. Gorn; 7 pp, 9 illus; 1946. (Box 9)
  - B-135 Wehrkreis Prague (Apr.-May 1945). By General der lnfanterie Rudolf Toussaint; 2pp. (Box 9)
  - B-136 National Redoubt (Wehrkreis VII SS and Police) (1944-45). By General der Waffen-SS Karl Frhr. von Eberstein; 4 pp; 1946. (Box 9)
  - B-137 The Hamburg Military Police (1945). By Generalmajor Theobald Thier; 3 pp; 1946. (Box 9)
  - B-138 Employment of Field Headquarters 198 in Western Hungary and Steiermark (22 Mar.-8 May 1945). By Generalmajor Ullrich Bormann; 12 pp; 1946. (Box 9)
  - B-139 Fighting in West Hungary and East Steiermark in, the Area of the Sixth Army (25 Mar.-8 May 1945). By Generalleutnant Walter Krause; 12 pp; 1946. By the Sixth Army Rear Area commander, who also led a heterogeneous division group.. (Box 9)
  - B-140 National Redoubt. By General der Waffen-SS Otto Hofmann; 4 pp; 1946. (Box 9)
  - B-141 Wehrkreis V Military Police (13 Apr.-5 May 1945). By Generalmajor Hermann Harttmann; 4 pp. (Box 9)
  - B-142 First Army Rear Area (22 Mar.-14 May 1945). By Generalleutnant Otto Kohl; 4 pp, 2 illus; 1946. (Box 9)
  - B-143 Activity of Army Administrative Headquarters 197 (22 Mar.-8 May 1945). By Johannes Hahn; 12 pp; 1946.. (Box 9)
  - B-144 LXXXII Corps--" Straggler" Staff (18 Apr.-2 May 1945). By Generalleutnant Benignus Dippold; 5 pp; 1946. (Box 9)
  - B-145 Defense of Nuremberg (12-16 Apr. 1945). By Generalleutnant Benignus Dippold; 5 pp, 2 illus; 1946. Preparations for the defense of the city. (Box 9)
  - B-146 Signal Communications, Civilian Liaison. By Generalmajor (Luftwaffe) Otto Prinz; 3 pp. Organization and duties of the Armed Forces Signal "Kommandanturas." (Box 9)
  - B-147 Army Group H (10 Nov. 1944-10 Mar. 1945. By Oberst i.G. Rolf Geyer; to 49 pp, 4 illus; 1946. A historical study by the army group operations (Box 9)